

ILYAS KERBAL

• DETAILS •

ERRACHIDIA Morocco +212 681564731 kerbalsc@gmail.com

LINKS

Linkedin

GitHub

Portfolio

° SKILLS °

Android Development

Android SDK

Git

Kotlin

Android Studio

Automated Testing

Test-driven development

Firebase

SQL

Continuous Integration

Agile and Scrum

PROFILE

Software engineer with **6+ years of experience** in **Android development**. I have worked on numerous **freelance projects** and built and *published many apps* on my own. I can adapt to both self-starting and collaborative environments while focusing on **high-quality results** under **strict deadlines**. Sincere about starting my new journey and tackling android challenges for the years to come.

EDUCATION

Android Kotlin Developer, Android Development, Udacity

February 2022 — May 2022

- Taught by Google Engineers, learning the latest and best practice Android development techniques from MVVM architecture to dependency injection and testing.
- Worked with more than 19 projects and built 5 on my own.

Front End Web Development, treehouse

January 2020 — December 2020

Engineer's degree, School of Information Sciences (ESI), Rabat, Morocco

January 2016 — October 2020

Data engineering and computer science.

Math / Physics (MPSI), Ibn Tahir High School, Errachidia, Morocco

January 2014 — December 2016

Mathematics BAC, SIJILMASSA high school, Errachidia, Morocco

January 2011 — December 2014

COURSES

Java Android Development, Treehouse

February 2016 — May 2016

TOEIC - English

EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

Android Engineer at BidSys, Rabat, Morocco

July 2020 — June 2022

Freelance Android Developer at UpWork

August 2016 — May 2022

RELEVANT INTERNSHIPS

Mobile Developer at LE DIGIMENTAL LIMITED, Casablanca, Morocco

January 2020 — July 2020

ATTENDED EVENTS

O DevFest, Google Developer Groups (GDG), Kuala Lumpur, Malaysia

December 2019

★ RELEVANT PROJECTS

Who is using my WIfi?

Android (native) app lets users discover and keep track of devices connected to the network. The app received a total of **6+ Million downloads** on Play Store.

https://gitlab.com/ilyasKerbal/wumw

PostureWise

Android & IOS app built using Flutter. The app helps fix bad posture by providing short, simple exercises arranged in 30 days program.

https://gitlab.com/ilyasKerbal/posturewise

Political Preparedness

An application that provides civic data intended to provide educational opportunities to the U.S. electorate using data provided by the Google Civic Information API.

Location Reminder

TODO list app with location reminders that remind the user to do something when the user is at a specific location.